Once upon a time, there was a man who died.
The story the man wrote was about a happy prince
who loved everyone and was loved by everyone.
The people fought, each wanting him to love them and them alone.
And an evil raven pecked at the loving hearts of one person after another.
The more the prince loved them and tried to save them,
the more the people's love just fed the raven,
In the end, the raven thought,
I'd like to try eating the prince's heart,
the most delicious one of all.
Thank you.
Hey.
Alright, just what's going on?
And who is she?
Why did the story just...
I will make sure it doesn't double back again.
Fakir, what are you trying to accomplish?
Wait a minute.
You're not thinking of rewriting the story that's controlling this town, are you?
All I want is the power to protect people. That's it.
Altor, can I ask you something?
What's that?
My power, is it really something that makes stories into reality?
You're sure I'm not writing things that will become reality anyway?
The two are part of the same power.
Listen to me, if your power is immature, then of course it's going to be swayed by reality.
But if you develop a strong power, reality should start bending towards and obeying your stories.
It would then be a trivial matter to move on to manipulating the fates of all mankind.
The power to protect, eh?
Did I actually write down a story that saved her with my own power?
Or was I made to write it?
Her feelings for Mewto are spilling up through my hand and out onto the page.
Even though I couldn't write one letter of a story about Mewto, I could write a story to save hers if it were flowing from me.
But the story I need to write is about Mewto.
I meant Fakir's?
That manuscript… He said he wrote that for me.
Oh, Uzzurra!
I guess you got back safe too, huh?
Fakir!
So you're awake. You're hungry, right?
Yeah.
Well, that's the story you wrote.
It's a story that's over now.
The story about me that Fakir wrote for me.
I kind of wanted to read it.
But I'm really glad you're able to write stories now, Fakir.
And then when I told him that I thought the five gates had heart shards in them, he said congratulations.
So basically, those shards are the only ones sealing away the raven.
Now we can go and get them all!
We could. It would also restore the raven.
Calm down, will you?
It's a bridge we'll have to cross eventually, and if we don't get moving, Mewto might not be able to return to normal.
Yeah, that's true.
I guess even if the raven is restored, it'll be no problem now that you've got the power of stories, right?
You do your best.
That's right. Mewto has Fakir and he has Princess Tutu.
He'll never lose to the raven.
And I'm sure Roo will return to normal too.
Roo?
Good morning, Prince.
Prince, huh?
Hmm.
Prince, you're hungry, aren't you?
I'm hungry.
I need to meet me.
Hello, Crane.
Yes, I am hungry.
Stop!
Now what did you do that for? You love me, don't you?
You don't love me?
My love has done nothing but make you into this.
I have no right to love you.
Is that... Mewto?
Let's dance.
My Prince.
Of course.
Oh, Prince.
I don't think I've ever seen Roo dance so, so sadly.
Do you remember all the pas de deux we danced together?
You're my Prince.
That's right.
Yep. After all, that's what Father said.
The Prince who sealed me away deserves our hatred.
But, he is the one Prince that you should marry, Crane.
A Prince who loves everyone should be able to sincerely love even an ugly, pitiful girl like you.
You really think?
Yes, I really do.
The only time I was happy was the time that I spent with you.
Mewto! Mewto!
Mewto!
I wanted you to look at me alone.
I wanted never to be without you. Not even for a moment.
Hey, look! Is this pretty?
Yes.
I have to get back to Fakir soon. He'll be getting worried.
What? Wait, watch me!
I'm sorry.
No! Stay and watch me, please!
I practiced as hard as I could!
But you... you didn't.
Crane, go to the human world as a human girl and win the Princess love.
Yes, Father.
And if you should ever get hold of a shard of the Prince's heart, I need you to bring it to me at once.
Because I have a task to perform in preparation for your wedding to him.
I will.
Today is the first day of lessons for those in the Beginner's class. So I'll take this time to talk about ballet and marriage. Ballet and marriage are inextricably intertwined!
Hello, Rue.
We can see each other every day now, my Prince.
Muto!
Call Muto Prince again and I'll make sure you regret it.
Then I won't do it as long as you agree not to get in our way.
I didn't want anyone to know I was a crow, so I sealed away the memories.
My beloved daughter.
I honestly was convinced that I was father's daughter!
I'm a fool. There's no way a mere human like me could marry the Prince from the story.
So, all this time, Rue really wasn't Kreyi at all.
Shall we dance, Kreyi?
Rue?
Duck?
Why does Muto look like that?
You saw?
That's right. It was my fault.
Go ahead, laugh at the foolish girl tricked by a raven.
I wouldn't laugh at you.
Liar! I know you're thinking this serves me right.
No, I'm not.
Leave me be.
Rue, inside the five town gates are the heart shards that are sealing away the raven.
If we return them, I know Muto will go back to normal.
They're sealing the raven away?
No, you mustn't!
Should the raven be restored and the Prince get his heart in its entirety,
he'll give his heart over to the raven.
What?
But if the Prince goes back to normal…
What if he doesn't go back to normal? What then?
But I…
The raven was using us to make the Prince give him his heart.
That's all he wanted!
No way, but then…
Listen to me, don't do anything else!
Rue, I…
I'm begging you, please stop!
If it were me, if I were Princess Tutu,
I'd never give him his heart back.
Now what? What should I do?
What a shame for you, little duck!
The story won't end that easily, you know!
First, that's not really tragic enough!
Now what?
Quack!
What's wrong with duck, Sora?
Duck doesn't know.
Huh?
That's the myself who's a puppet, Sora!
There's a thing she doesn't know.
A thing she doesn't know?
A thing, Sora?
A truth that should have been revealed after the Prince's heart was stolen by the raven.
The prince from the prince and the raven has become real!
I see.
And the raven has become real as well, and is being restored as we speak!
This town really is being controlled by stories!
My hypothesis was right on the mark!
I'm a knight who was given the fate of death in vain.
My sword would prove useless in protecting the prince.
So you want to write?
Yes.
Well to be frank, you have no hope of rewriting Drosselmayr's stories at your level of power.
If you're only where the story is writing itself through you,
then there's no way you can make your stories reality.
I'm aware of that.
That's why I'm asking you for your help, Autor.
And just why should I have to do that for you?
Listen, I need your knowledge.
And all I'm saying is, why should I?
What?
Mewto.
What does Mewto want me to do?
What?
Uzzurath?
You're going to stop being duck, aren't you, Zora?
What?
My self told me so, Zora.
My smell?
My self is here inside me, Zora.
The sound of Uzzurath's heart.
This music is...
Miss Ada!
It's been a while, hasn't it, duck?
There's a thing the duck doesn't know.
What?
The duck's... pendant.
My pendant?
Yes.
That's the last of the prince's heart shards.
It resonates with the heart shards because it is a heart shard itself.
That shard is what awakens Princess Tutu.
Princess Tutu, the only one who can give the prince's heart back to him.
I get it.
Before the prince shattered his heart, it was his will that he'd someday get it back.
Isn't that right?
However, whether or not the duck returns that heart shard to the prince depends on her own will.
Miss Ada!
My will is the same as Mewtwo's.
Qua...
You look like you feel better, Zora.
The Pendant, you're giving it to the Prince Sora, and then you'll go back to being a Duck Sora, and then we won't be able to talk to each other anymore, Zora.
And even if I put water on you, you won't change back, Zora?
Yeah, that's right. That me's the real me.
You're really a Duck, Zora?
Now don't cry, okay?
Okay, Zora.
Zora, no, that cursed Edel had to butt in. That was the secret I was saving for my last bit of fun.
Well, no matter with things as they are, they won't be able to escape the tragedy.
Ohh!
Aaaaahhh!
Ahh!
Ah memang, ehm...
Biri steal!
Ne of Toph!
Won't you dance with me?
Why are you so, so frightened of me?
He's right.
Just now I was afraid of Mewtwo.
Whoa, dearie!
The prince!
Can you dance with me?
When I'm not dancing with someone,
I'm uneasy and lonely.
And it hurts so much I can't stand it.
My prince...
I'm sorry, my prince.
You're suffering because of the raven's blood.
The hearts of these birds hurt people.
Even the people you love.
The more love you have for them,
the more pain you cause them.
With my own hands,
I've thrown into chaos
this heart of yours that loves everyone.
Every part of this has been my fault,
just because I wanted to have your love all to myself.
I'm so sorry!
Rue!
Tutu!
This pendant that transforms me into Princess Tutu
is also a shard from the prince's heart.
So it is the will of the prince himself
to have all of his heart returned to him.
I'll act according to the prince's will.
Let's both believe in the prince.
I'll act according to the prince.
I'll act according to the prince's will.
Let's both believe in the prince.
All right then.
Shards, answer me.
Here I am.
Look at what you've become.
So this is the prince?
How lamentable.
What?
Doesn't it seem like it's already too late?
What can we do but return to our original heart?
Let's prepare ourselves.
The raven is about to revive.
Let us not waver.
Princess Tutu, thank you.
However, if,
even after I go back inside my heart
and the raven's curse has not been lifted,
I ask that you please not return to our original heart.
What?
Doesn't it seem like it's already too late?
What can we do but return to our original heart?
Let's prepare ourselves.
The raven is about to revive.
Let us not waver.
Princess Tutu, thank you.
However, if,
even after I go back inside my heart
I ask that you please not return
the final heart shard.
But I...
If that happens, please find a way to lift the curse.
Quickly.
But that's...
We don't have a moment to spare.
Now...
If that is what the prince wills...
My prince...
We finally meet again.
So this... is the raven?
Now, Crahi...
Bring the prince here.
No!
What?
Then you don't mind losing my love?
My father is no raven.
And as for you...
You're a liar!
Hmm...
You found out.
I've raised you drinking my noble blood ever since you were a baby.
But in the end, you're nothing more than a foolish human girl.
It's bad enough you couldn't turn the prince's affections towards you like your blood demanded.
But to think you succumb to love...
I have no need of raven's blood!
When I was Rue...
That was when I was happiest.
What a waste of my time.
Now, prince!
Come to me on your own power.
Give me your heart.
You mustn't!
You mustn't go!
No!
Please don't go!
Don't go!
Prince!
Please, please wait.
No!
Let the prince go!
Don't eat the prince's heart!
Let it go and eat my heart instead!
Please, I love you!
My prince!
I have ever since I was little!
I've always loved you!
What is this feeling I have?
You dare interfere?
This frail earnest love...
I must...
I must protect this love.
Tutu...
Were you the one who helped me?
Maybe.
For you to love him so much, you'd give up your life.
You're a foolish girl to the end.
When that happens, I'll go back to being just a bird.
Then I won't ever study ballet with everybody again.
That's fine, isn't it? After all, that's who you really are.
I would like for you to return my final heart shot.
Sayo, I have another question. Do you think you'll love me?
Let's go back to being our true selves now.
Goodbye now, Mewtwo. Goodbye.
All you children who love stories, come gather round!
Goodbye.